{"name": "68C  2010-6", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The face of a fair spinner is divided into 24 sectors, each of which is 1 of 5 colors: Blue, Purple, Green, Orange, or Red. The table below gives each color and the probability that the spinner, when spun, will stop on that color. On which color shown in the table is the spinner LEAST likely to stop?             ", "choices": {"A": "Blue", "B": "Purple", "C": "Green", "D": " Orange", "E": "Red"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Saul goes shopping and decides to buy 4 shirts at a price of $20.08 each. Which of the following expressions gives the total price, in dollars, of the 4 shirts?", "choices": {"A": " 4 + 20 + 0.08", "B": "4 - (20 - 0.08)", "C": "4 + (20 - 0.08)", "D": "4(20) - 4(0.08)", "E": "4(20) + 4(0.08)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to x\u00b2 - 9 \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "(x - 3)(x - 3)", "C": "(x - 3)(x + 3)", "D": "(x - 1)(x + 9)", "E": "(2x - 3)(2x + 3)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. In the figure below, E is on ,  is perpendicular to , and the measure of \u2220CED equals 38\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220AEB \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "38\u00b0", "B": "45\u00b0", "C": "52\u00b0", "D": "71\u00b0", "E": "76\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. Janeece's average heart rate is 70 beats per minute. At this rate, how many times, to the nearest thousand, dose her heart beat in 7 days?", "choices": {"A": "12,000", "B": "29,000", "C": "353,000", "D": "706,000", "E": "42,336,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. If x = -7, what is the value of  ?", "choices": {"A": "41", "B": "", "C": "6", "D": "-6", "E": "-8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. A point at (-6, 11) in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane is shifted right 11 units and down 6 units. What are the new coordinates of the point?", "choices": {"A": "(-17, 17)", "B": "(0, 0)", "C": "(5, 5)", "D": "(5, 17)", "E": "(17, 17)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. If 7 + 4x = 31, then 3x = ?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "18", "C": "20", "D": "23", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. When Jamar purchased a houseplant for his room, it was 4 inches in height. For the next 6 weeks, the houseplant grew taller at a rate of  inches per week. Which of the following graphs best represents the houseplant's height, h inches, versus the number of weeks, w, after Jamar purchased the houseplant?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. A function h of the variables a and b is defined as . What is the value of h(3, 2) ?", "choices": {"A": "-1", "B": "0", "C": "1", "D": "3", "E": "17"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. In the figure below, \u2220BAC measures 35\u00b0, \u2220ABC measures 115\u00b0, and points B, C, and D are collinear. What is the measure of \u2220ACD ?", "choices": {"A": "115\u00b0", "B": "120\u00b0", "C": "125\u00b0", "D": "145\u00b0", "E": "150\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Koji had $50.00 to spend on school supplies. He bought a schoolbag for $18.50, a box of pencils for $2.50, and a package of pens for $4.00. Koji still must buy b binders at $3.50 each and n spiral notebooks at $0.75 each. Which of the following inequalities represents how many binders and spiral notebooks he can buy with the remaining money?(Note: No tax is charged on school supplies.)", "choices": {"A": "3.5b + 0.75n \u2264 75 ", "B": "3.5b + 0.75n &lt; 50", "C": "3.5b + 0.75n \u2264 50 ", "D": "3.5b + 0.75n &lt; 25", "E": "3.5b + 0.75n \u2264 25"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. In the figure below, \u2220AEB is congruent to \u2220DEC and BE is congruent to CE. One of the following angle congruences completes what is needed to prove as directly as possible that \u25b3ABE is congruent to \u25b3DCE by applying the Angle-Side-Angle (ASA) property. Which one? ", "choices": {"A": "\u2220ABE \u224c \u2220CDE ", "B": "\u2220ABE \u224c \u2220DCE", "C": "\u2220BAE \u224c \u2220BCD", "D": "\u2220BCE \u224c \u2220BCD", "E": "\u2220BCE \u224c \u2220BEC"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. Of the 40 marbles in Dakarai's bag, all are solid in color and 16 are blue. The probability that he will randomly choose a yellow marble from the bag is . How many yellow marbles are in Dakarai's bag?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "5", "D": "16", "E": "24"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. A square and a rectangle have the same area. The length of the rectangle is 36 centimeters, and the width of the rectangle is 4 centimeters. What is the length, in centimeters, of a side of the square?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "12", "C": "20", "D": "80", "E": "144"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. Arita played in 7 softball games. In the first 4 games, she had 2, 3, 1, and 3 hits, respectively. In the last 3 games, she had a total of 6 hits. What was her average number of hits per game in the 7 games?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "", "C": "3", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. A test has 50 questions and is worth 130 points. It consists of x 5-point questions and y 2-point questions. Which of the following systems of equations, when solved, gives the number of each type of question that is on the test?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. For what value of t is 4.5 =  true?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "7", "D": "11", "E": "18"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. (4a + 7b + 6c) - (6a + 6b - 3c) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "-2a + b + 9c", "B": "-2a + b - 3c", "C": "2a + 13b + 9c", "D": "-2a + 13b -3c", "E": "8abc"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. What is the least common multiple of 50, 30, and 70?", "choices": {"A": "50", "B": "105", "C": "150", "D": "1,050", "E": "105,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. The number of bricks, B, needed to build a wall of length L feet and uniform height H feet can be found by the equation B = 7LH. A wall of uniform height that is 30 feet long is constructed using 420 bricks. What is the height, in feet, of the wall? ", "choices": {"A": "0.2", "B": "1.4", "C": "2", "D": "14", "E": "60"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. What is the slope of any line parallel to the line 5x + 7y = 7?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "5", "E": "7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. In the figure below, right triangle \u25b3ABC has an area of 20 square inches, BC is 5 inches long, and \u2220B is a right angle. What is the length, in inches, of AB ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": "5", "D": "7.5", "E": "8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. Reuben is standing 300 yards due east from the flagpole at his school and 400 yards due south from the oak tree in his front yard. What is the straight-line distance, in yards, from the flagpole to the oak tree?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "100", "D": "500", "E": "700"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. |9(-6) + 5(4)| = ?", "choices": {"A": "-34", "B": "12", "C": "23", "D": "34", "E": "74"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. Given 6x - y = x + 5y, which of the following is an expression for y ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. The lengths of the corresponding sides of 2 similar right triangles are in the ratio of 2:7. The hypotenuse of the smaller triangle is 10 inches long. How many inches long is the hypotenuse of the larger triangle?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "14", "C": "15", "D": "19", "E": "35"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Which of the following is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Use the following information to answer questions 29-31.Kyla purchased 25 pieces of candy from Laszko's Candy Shop. Her purchase consists of 7 lollipops, 4 candy bars, 10 licorice sticks, and 4 gumballs. The unit price of each candy item is shown in the table below. Kyla's purchase, without sales tax, totaled $10.30. Laszko's charges an 8% sales tax on each purchase, which is calculated by multiplying the purchase total by 0.08 and rounding to the nearest $0.01.  29. Kyla gave the shop clerk $15.00. How much change should Kyla have received?", "choices": {"A": "$3.88", "B": "$4.35", "C": " $4.62", "D": "$4.70 ", "E": "$5.08"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Use the following information to answer questions 29-31.Kyla purchased 25 pieces of candy from Laszko's Candy Shop. Her purchase consists of 7 lollipops, 4 candy bars, 10 licorice sticks, and 4 gumballs. The unit price of each candy item is shown in the table below. Kyla's purchase, without sales tax, totaled $10.30. Laszko's charges an 8% sales tax on each purchase, which is calculated by multiplying the purchase total by 0.08 and rounding to the nearest $0.01.30. Without sales tax, what was the average price Kyla paid per piece of candy, to the nearest $0.01 ?", "choices": {"A": "$0.21", "B": "$0.25", "C": "$0.32", "D": "$0.41", "E": "$0.44"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. Use the following information to answer questions 29-31.Kyla purchased 25 pieces of candy from Laszko's Candy Shop. Her purchase consists of 7 lollipops, 4 candy bars, 10 licorice sticks, and 4 gumballs. The unit price of each candy item is shown in the table below. Kyla's purchase, without sales tax, totaled $10.30. Laszko's charges an 8% sales tax on each purchase, which is calculated by multiplying the purchase total by 0.08 and rounding to the nearest $0.01.31. Kyla offers to sell 2 of the 25 pieces of candy to her brother Virgil. She lets Virgil have a choice of 2 pieces of the same candy item or 1 piece each of 2 different candy items. Kyla will have Virgil pay the same total cost for the 2 pieces that he would pay for the 2 pieces at Laszko's. How many different total costs (in dollars) are possible for Virgil's choice of 2 pieces?", "choices": {"A": "8", "B": "10", "C": "12", "D": "14", "E": "16"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. The diameter of a circle is 36 yards, as shown in the figure below. What is the circumference of the circle, in yards?", "choices": {"A": "18\u03c0", "B": "36\u03c0", "C": "72\u03c0", "D": "324\u03c0", "E": "1,296\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. For all real x, ", "choices": {"A": "x\u00b2 + 4", "B": "x\u00b2 + 4x + 4 ", "C": "3x\u00b2 - 12", "D": "3x\u00b2 - 12x + 12 ", "E": "3x\u00b2 + 12x + 12 "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Which of the following is a solution statement for the inequality 6x - 6 &lt; 7 + 10x ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "x\">", "D": "x\">", "E": "x\">"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. The perimeter of a parallelogram is 68 inches, and 1 side measures 14 inches. lf it can be determined, what are the lengths, in inches, of the other 3 sides ?", "choices": {"A": "14, 13, 13", "B": "14, 14, 26", "C": "14, 20, 20", "D": "14, 27, 27", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. What is the slope of the line through both of the points (5,2) and (9,4) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane ?", "choices": {"A": "-7", "B": "-2", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "2"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. The hour and minute hands of the clock shown below move at constant speeds. What is the measure of the angle formed by the hour and minute hands at exactly 1:30 ?", "choices": {"A": "97.5\u00b0", "B": "120\u00b0C", "C": "122.5\u00b0", "D": "125\u00b0", "E": "135\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Use the following information to answer questions 38-40.Shown below is an inflatable display (on level ground) of a Lion's Crest Cola can. A blower pumps air into the display at an average rate of 600 cubic feet per minute as it inflates the display. When fully inflated, the display is a right circular cylinder with a diameter of 12 feet and a height of 20 feet. Also shown below is 1 of the support ropes that anchors the display. The rope is attached to the top of the display and has an angle of elevation of 55\u00b0. The volume of air in the fully inflated display is equal to the display's height times the area of 1 of the circular bases.38. Which of the following is closest to the length, in feet, of the support rope?(Note: sin 55\u00b0 \u2248 0.82; cos55\u00b0 \u2248 0.57; tan55\u00b0 \u2248 1.43) ", "choices": {"A": "24", "B": "29", "C": "32", "D": "35", "E": "40"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Use the following information to answer questions 38-40.Shown below is an inflatable display (on level ground) of a Lion's Crest Cola can. A blower pumps air into the display at an average rate of 600 cubic feet per minute as it inflates the display. When fully inflated, the display is a right circular cylinder with a diameter of 12 feet and a height of 20 feet. Also shown below is 1 of the support ropes that anchors the display. The rope is attached to the top of the display and has an angle of elevation of 55\u00b0. The volume of air in the fully inflated display is equal to the display's height times the area of 1 of the circular bases.39. The blower starts to pump air into the completely deflated display and continues until the display is fully inflated. To the nearest 0.1 minute, for how many minutes does the blower pump air?", "choices": {"A": "1.3", "B": "2.5", "C": "3.8", "D": "5.0", "E": "5.3"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Use the following information to answer questions 38-40.Shown below is an inflatable display (on level ground) of a Lion's Crest Cola can. A blower pumps air into the display at an average rate of 600 cubic feet per minute as it inflates the display. When fully inflated, the display is a right circular cylinder with a diameter of 12 feet and a height of 20 feet. Also shown below is 1 of the support ropes that anchors the display. The rope is attached to the top of the display and has an angle of elevation of 55\u00b0. The volume of air in the fully inflated display is equal to the display's height times the area of 1 of the circular bases.40. Inflatable Schemes, Inc., will manufacture a new inflatable display of a Lion's Crest Cola can that is geometrically similar to the display shown in the figure. The new display will have a height of 35 feet. What will be the diameter, in feet, of the new display?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "21", "C": "23", "D": "27", "E": "32"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. The area of a rectangular garden in a city park is 162 square yards. The length of the garden is twice its width. What is the perimeter, in yards, of the garden?", "choices": {"A": "27", "B": "36", "C": "54", "D": "162", "E": "324"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. While shopping, Ashton decided to purchase a shirt on sale that was marked down 40% from its original price of $10.00. At the checkout, he used an in-store coupon for 10% off the sale price. What was the final price of the shirt before any tax was added?", "choices": {"A": "$3.60", "B": "$4.00 ", "C": "$4.40 ", "D": "$5.00 ", "E": "$5.40"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, the graph of which of the following equations has the line x = 2 as a vertical asymptote?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. For what (x,y) pair is the matrix equation below true?", "choices": {"A": "(6,0) ", "B": "(5,5)", "C": "(5,-2)", "D": "(4,7)", "E": "(1,4)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The marketing students at Fort Link Business Academy took a placement test for an accounting class. The mean of the test scores is 100 and the standard deviation is 15. In order to be accepted into the accounting class, a student must have attained a test score that is at least 1 standard deviation above the mean. What is the lowest test score a student could attain and still be accepted into the accounting class?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "16", "C": "101", "D": "115", "E": "116"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. Two angles are coterminal if they have the same initial and terminal sides. For instance, the angles shown below with measures 45\u00b0 and 405\u00b0 are coterminal.An angle with measure 30\u00b0 is coterminal with a second angle. Which of the following measures could be that of the second angle?", "choices": {"A": "270\u00b0", "B": "300\u00b0", "C": "330\u00b0", "D": "360\u00b0", "E": "390\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, the midpoint of CD is at (5,-7) and point C is at (3,-11). For point D at (a,b), what is the value of a + b ?", "choices": {"A": "-14", "B": "-10", "C": "-5", "D": "4", "E": "6"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. An airplane flies the 200 miles from Fairhaven to Locksboro along a straight line in a direction (shown below) that is 25\u00b0 clockwise () from due north. To the nearest mile, Locksboro is how many miles due east and how many miles due north from Fairhaven?(Note: sin 25\u00b0 \u2248 0.423, cos 25\u00b0 \u2248 0.906) ", "choices": {"A": "due east: 85;   due north: 181", "B": "due east: 100;   due north: 173", "C": "due east: 141;   due north: 141", "D": "due east: 173;   due north: 100", "E": "due east: 181;   due north: 85"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The point (a,b) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane lies on a curve that is symmetric with respect to the y-axis. Which of the following points must also lie on that curve?", "choices": {"A": "(-a,-b)", "B": "(-a,b)", "C": "(a,-b)", "D": "(-b,a)", "E": "(b,a)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. In the figure below, the square has side length 8 centimeters. Each vertex of the square is the center of a circle. The circles are congruent, and each circle is tangent to 2 of the other circles. The region that is interior to the square and exterior to all 4 circles is shaded. What is the area, to the nearest centimeter, of the shaded region?", "choices": {"A": "51", "B": "39", "C": "32", "D": "25", "E": "14"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. The perimeter of a rectangle is P units and the width is w units. The length of the rectangle is x units longer than the width. Which of the following equations expresses x in terms of P and w ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. An angle with measure \u03b8 such that  is in standard position with its terminal side extending into Quadrant II as shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. What is the value of cos \u03b8  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. Let a and b be real numbers. If (a + b)\u00b2 = a\u00b2 + b\u00b2, it must be true that:", "choices": {"A": "either a or b is zero.", "B": "both a and b are zero.", "C": "both a and b are positive.", "D": "a is positive and b is negative.", "E": "a is negative and b is positive."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. The C &amp; F Company manufactures cameras and rolls of film. The constraints on C &amp; F's weekly production are shown on the coordinate plane below. The shaded region contains the feasible combinations of the number of cameras and the number of rolls of film produced in 1 week. Each vertex of the shaded region has integer coordinates (in thousands). The company makes a profit of $3 per camera sold and $1 per roll of film sold. Within the given constraints, what is the greatest possible profit, in dollars, from 1 week of C &amp; F's production?", "choices": {"A": "$9,000 ", "B": "$10,000 ", "C": "$12,000 ", "D": "$14,000 ", "E": "$20,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. In the figure below, lines a and b are parallel, the angle measure y is in degrees, and \u22201 and \u22202 have the same measure. In terms of y, which of the following is equivalent to the degree measure of \u22203 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "y\u00b0", "C": "90\u00b0 - y\u00b0", "D": "90\u00b0 - ", "E": " 189\u00b0 - y\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. In the figure below, the vertices of rectangle BCDE lie on the circle and the vertices of rhombus FGHI are the midpoints of the sides of rectangle BCDE. Point A is at the center of the circle, rectangle, and rhombus.The radius of the circle is 4 feet. How long is a side of the rhombus, in feet?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "6", "E": "8"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. If f(x) = , and g(x) = x + 1, which of the following number lines shows the domain of f(g(x)) ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. Which of the following is equivalent to |x - 1| &lt; B ?", "choices": {"A": "x - 1 \uff1c B and 1 - x \uff1c B", "B": "x - 1 \uff1c B and 1 - x \uff1e B", "C": "x - 1 \uff1e B and 1 - x \uff1c B", "D": "x + 1 \uff1c B and 1 - x \uff1c B", "E": "x + 1 \uff1c B and 1 - x \uff1e B"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. The area, A, of a circle varies directly with the square of the radius, r. One of the following graphs shows the area, A, of a circle as the radius varies in the (r,A) coordinate plane. Which graph is it?(Note: The (r,A) plane is the standard (x,y) coordinate plane with r along the horizontal axis and A along the vertical axis.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. Susan discovered by trial and error that one root of the equation 2x\u00b3 - 9x\u00b2 + 16x - 12 = 0 is 2. What are the other roots?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}]}